=== Inline Text Direction ===
Contributors: Almashroo
Tags: arabic, bidi, inline text direction, direction
Requires at least: 2.7
Tested up to: 2.8.4
Stable tag: 1.0

Changes the direction of inline text that is written as "RTL" that are embedded within Latin languages that are written as "RTL". and vice versa.

== Description ==

Inline Text Direction plugin for WordPress changes the direction of inline foreign text that is written from "Right to Left" that are embedded within Latin languages that are written from "Left to Right". and vice versa.

In general, when foreign text that has a different directional run than the paragraph that is embedded within, it’ll look very badly, that even sometimes, it’s hard to understand the paragraph due to this mix.

تقوم إضافة "اتجاه النص المضمن" لنظام WordPress بتغيير اتجاه النصوص الأجنبية التي تُكتب من "اليسار إلى اليمين" داخل الفقرات العربية والتي تُكتب من "اليمين إلى اليسار"، أو العكس.

في العادة، وعند دمج الكلمات الأجنبية في الفقرات العربية تظهر بشكل سيء، ويتغير اتجاه النصوص، بحيث في بعض الأحيان يصعب فهم المعنى لتداخل هذه النصوص ببعضها البعض.

[arabic_homepage](http://www.almashroo.com/projects/wordpress/plugins/inline-text-direction/ar/ "موقع الإضافة باللغة العربية")
[english_homepage](http://www.almashroo.com/projects/wordpress/plugins/inline-text-direction/en/ "Plugin Home Page for this plugin")

== Installation ==

To install this plugin, you need to do the following:

1. Unzip the downloaded file from the WordPress plugins directory.
1. Upload the unzipped "**inline-text-direction**" directory to your WordPress plugin directory "wp-content/plugins".
1. Activate the plugin.
1. Optional: You’ll find under "Options" a new link to control this plugin.

لتثبيت هذه الإضافة، عليك اتباع الخطوات التالية:

1. فك ضغط الملف المضغوط المحمّل من قسم إضافات WordPress.
1. رفع المجلد "**inline-text-direction**" إلى الخادم في مسار إضافات WordPress وهو "/wp-content/plugins"
1. تفعيل الإضافة من لوحة التحكم.
1. اختياري: ستجد تحت "الخيارات" رابطاً جديداً لتغيير خيارات إضافة “اتجاه النص المضمن”، يمكنك التعديل عليها بما يتناسب مع الموقع.


== Frequently Asked Questions ==


== Screenshots ==

1. inline-text-direction-control-editor-ar.png
2. inline-text-direction-control-index-ar.png
3. inline-text-direction-control-ar.png
4. inline-text-direction-control-editor-en.png
5. inline-text-direction-control-index-en.png
6. inline-text-direction-control-en.png

== Changelog ==

= 1.0 =
* Initial public release.

== Usage ==

In the Visual Editor (tinyMCE), You can select the foreign inline text you want to chnage the direction for, then, you can click the button "**The direction of foreign inline text**" which you can find on the toolbar.

In the HTML editor, you can also change the direction of inline text, and you can do by selecting the desired text, and then click on "**><**" which you can find on the toolbar.

في محرر النصوص المتطور tinyMCE، يمكنك تحديد النص الأجنبي المراد تحويل اتجاهه، ومن ثمّ الضغط على زر "**تغيير توجيه النص المضمن**"، والذي ستجده من بين الأزرار في أعلى المحرر.

في محرر HTML، يمكنك أيضاً تحديد النص الأجنبي المراد تحويل اتجاهه، ومن ثمّ الضغط على على "**><**"، والذي ستجده من بين الأزرار في أعلى المحرر.
